[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 32]
[제32화]
I'm sorry.
미안해
I can accept any punishment,
어떤 처벌이든 다 받을게
and I can also withdraw from the match.
시합도 기권할 수 있어
But I don't want my personal matters
하지만 나 하나 때문에
to affect Hengjiu.
팀에 피해를 주고 싶진 않아
Do you have any other questions?
더 물어볼 거 있어?
About this, you can decide for yourselves.
이 일은 너희가 직접 결정해
Ms. Lin, Coach.
린 선생님, 코치님
We want to take some time to think it over.
저희 고민해 보고 말씀드릴게요
No problem.
그렇게 해
Let's go.
가요
I'll take him out first.
일단 얘 데리고 나갈게
Let me know when you've made a decision.
결정하면 말해줘
-Okay.
- 네
Let's go.
가자
I don't get it.
이해가 안 되네
He's the one who did something wrong.
잘못은 쟤가 했는데
What is there for us to consider?
우리가 뭘 더 고민해?
Wrong is wrong.
잘못한 건 잘못한 거지
I know what you guys mean.
다들 무슨 생각인지 알아
But I think we should treat different things separately.
근데 이건 그거랑 다른 문제야
Besides, he's our opponent.
게다가 쟨 우리 상대 팀이잖아
Don't act like a saint, okay?
괜히 착한 척 좀 하지 마
He was shedding tears just now.
지금은 불쌍한 척하는데
Who knows if he was just acting?
저게 연기인지 아닌지 어떻게 알아?
He just wanted us to forgive him
우리가 용서해 주길 바라는 거잖아
and pretend nothing happened.
없던 일로 해달라는 거지
If we report him,
우리가 신고하면
what will be the consequences?
어떻게 될까?
This could affect him for the rest of his life.
걘 평생 꼬리표가 붙을 거야
I think we should give him a chance.
그래도 한 번은 기회를 주는 게 맞아
If we give him a chance,
우리가 걔한테 기회를 주면
who's going to give us a chance?
우리 기회는 누가 챙겨주는데?
Fu,
야, 푸신수
if Hengjiu loses him,
헝주에서 쟤가 빠지면
our chances of winning will be much higher.
우리 우승 확률이 훨씬 높아져
Right.
그렇지
Have you all forgotten what you said?
다들 본인이 했던 말은 잊었어?
We play football to win.
축구는 승리를 위한 거라며?
Everyone,
얘들아
do you remember what Director Qian said?
첸 주임님 말씀 기억 안 나?
We are about to take the college entrance exam.
우리 곧 대입 시험이야
As long as we beat Hengjiu,
헝주만 이기면
we'll have a chance at special admission.
수시 전형 기회가 생긴다고
Qin,
친아오
what do you think?
네 생각은 어때?
I don't know what to say.
나도 뭐라고 해야 할지 모르겠다
But if I had to say,
근데 굳이 말하자면
I think...
난 그래도
I still want to beat that Qin Qiechu on the field.
친체추 그 자식을 이기고 싶어
He slapped us in the face,
걔가 우릴 엿 먹였으니
so we have to hit back, right?
우리도 갚아줘야지, 안 그래?
Come on.
아니
Is there something wrong with your brain?
너 돌았어?
Are you talking to me?
내가?
Isn't there?
아니야, 그럼?
This match is related to our future.
이 경기에 우리 미래가 걸렸어
If you don't want to go to college,
너 대학 가기 싫다고
could you please not drag us down?
남들 발목까진 잡지 마
I drag you down?
내가 네 발목을 잡아?
I'll say it one last time.
다시 한번 말해줄 테니
Listen carefully.
똑똑히 들어
With your terrible grades, do you even need me to drag you down?
네 성적이면 내가 발목 잡고 할 것도 없어
-Enough! -Alright, alright!
- 됐어 - 됐어, 그만해
You're desperate to go to college, huh?
대학에 가고 싶어서 미쳤구나?
Qin Ao.
친아오
-Alright, alright. -Don't touch me!
- 됐어, 그만해 - 만지지 마
How about...
아니면
we use Robert's Rules of Order?
우리 그냥 로버트 의사 규칙으로 하자
I agree.
나도 찬성이야
What do you think?
다들 어때?
Alright.
좋아
Let's start voting.
그럼 표결 시작할게
For those who think
신고해야 한다고
we should report him,
생각하는 사람은
stand on this side.
이쪽에 서고
For those who think we should let it go,
그냥 넘어가고 싶은 사람은
Do you want to sit down and wait?
앉아서 기다릴래?
Coach, Ms. Lin.
코치님, 린 선생님
-I… -Have you made up your minds?
- 저 - 의논 다 했어?
You guys talk.
그럼 너희끼리 얘기해
Okay.
네
Come in with me.
들어와
Is it true that no matter the outcome,
어떤 결과가 나오든
you can accept it?
다 받아들이실 수 있는 거지?
Given the current situation,
지금 이 상황
it's not really up to me, is it?
내가 결정할 수 있는 게 아니잖아, 그렇지?
Yes.
맞아
By a vote of 9 to 2,
9 대 2로 통과했어
we decided not to report you
신고하지 않고
or call the police.
경찰에도 알리지도 않기로
You can go now.
이제 가 봐
Why?
왜?
Did you think
우리가 꼭 널
we would definitely report you?
신고할 거라고 생각했냐?
I know.
알아
Even though you didn't want us to report you,
우리가 신고하지 않길 바라면서도
deep down,
속으로는
you probably didn't believe
우리가 이 기회를 절대
we'd give up this chance.
포기하지 않을 거라고 생각했겠지
Alright.
됐어
I'll be blunt.
그냥 솔직하게 말할게
We do want to win,
우리도 이기고 싶어
but we want to beat you on the field.
근데 경기장에서 너희를 이기고 싶어
Also,
그리고
that brat Qin Qiechu
친체추 그 자식이
has always been talking about us behind our backs.
맨날 우리 뒤에서 씹어대서
We've wanted to crush him for a long time.
진작부터 박살 내고 싶었거든
Just like that, the special admission spots are gone.
특별 전형 TO가 이렇게 날아가 버렸네
So you guys better not go easy on us.
그러니까 그때 가서 절대 봐주지 마
Or I'll regret it to death.
안 그러면 나 후회돼서 미칠 거야
Now do you know why?
이제 왜 그런지 알겠지?
Thank you.
고맙다
I'll give it my all.
나도 최선을 다할 거야
Right,
참
don't forget to sign the IOU.
차용증에 사인하는 거 잊지 마
This isn't a gift from me.
이거 그냥 주는 거 아니다
[IOU] [Debtor: Fang Sulun]
[차용증][차용인 팡쑤룬]
Keep it safe.
자
Here.
받아
It's yours.
네 거야
Thank you,
고마워
Lin Lu.
린루
What's wrong?
왜 그래요?
I'm so proud.
너무 자랑스러워요
I know.
알아요
Me too.
나도 그렇거든요
They've really grown up.
애들이 정말 다 컸네요
Then I'll...
그럼 우리
see you on the field.
경기장에서 보자
-Of course we will. -See you on the field.
- 물론이지 - 경기장에서 보자
See you on the field.
경기장에서 봐
Tell that brat Qin Qiechu
친체추한테 전해 줘
to rest well today.
오늘 잠 푹 자두라고
He might get knocked flat on the field tomorrow!
내일 경기장에서 내가 날려버릴 테니까
Okay, I'll pass it on.
응, 꼭 전해줄게
Be careful. You may get crushed by us then.
우리한테 털리지나 마라
They definitely will.
당연하지
-They definitely will be crushed by us. -I told you we would do our best,
- 무조건 우리가 이겨 - 최선을 다한다고 했잖아
so we definitely will.
진짜 제대로 붙어 보자
Okay, okay.
그래
This is the second clash between Yongchuan Hengjiu
융촨 헝주와 훙징 제8고의
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League No. 8 High School vs. Hengjiu]
[융촨 유소년 슈퍼 리그 제8고 대 헝주]
and Hongjing No. 8 High School.
두 번째 대결입니다
Who will be the champion?
과연 누가 우승컵을 차지할지
We'll soon find out.
오늘 밝혀질 텐데요
Both cheer squads are full of energy.
양 팀 응원단의 열기도 아주 대단합니다
[LIVE] [Hongjing No. 8 High][Yongchuan Hengjiu]
[현장 중계] [ 훙징 제8고][융촨 헝주]
I believe this match
오늘 경기
[Commentator]
[해설원]
will definitely not disappoint the audience.
절대 여러분을 실망시키지 않을 겁니다
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team]
[훙징 제8고 축구팀]
This is the 2nd clash between the two teams.
이번이 두 팀의 두 번째 맞대결인데요
[Victory for Hongjing]
[훙징 필승]
Will Hongjing No. 8 High School go all the way,
훙징 제8고가 이대로 끝까지 돌풍을 이어갈지
[Hold Your Head High, Hongjing's Pride]
[겸손 필요 없다 훙징의 자랑]
or will Yongchuan Hengjiu be crowned champions for the 6th time?
아니면 융촨 헝주가 6회 연속 우승을 차지할지
We'll find out in 90 minutes.
90분 후에 그 답이 공개됩니다
Both cheer squads are full of energy.
응원단의 열기도 활기차네요
I believe this match
오늘 경기는
will definitely not disappoint
현장에 오신 분들과
the audience here and in front of the TV.
안방에서 시청하시는 분들 모두를 만족시킬 겁니다
Yongchuan Hengjiu!
융촨 헝주!
[Invincible Yongchuan Hengjiu]
[융촨 헝주 백전백승]
-Go for it!
아자! 아자! 아자
Hongjing, Hongjing!
훙징, 훙징!
Champions of the universe!
우주 최강!
No. 8 High School
그라운드의 지배자!
rules the field!
우리 8고밖에 없다!
Go, go, go!
파이팅! 파이팅!
[VIP]
[귀빈석]
Father-in-law, this is Hengjiu's VIP area.
아버님, 여긴 헝주 팀 귀빈석이에요
What are you doing?
왜 여기서 그러세요?
So what?
그게 어때서?
I'm a hardcore fan of Hongjing.
난 훙징 팀 찐팬이야
What's wrong?
뭐?
Oh, wait.
그나저나
Who are you calling father-in-law?
누구더러 아버님이래?
You are the chairman of Hengjiu.
헝주 회장님이신데
It doesn't look good.
이러면 보기 안 좋아요
-It's not appropriate. -Yeah.
- 이미지 구긴다고요 - 맞아요
Right, it's not appropriate.
맞아, 이건 아닌 것 같아
I'll go over to Hongjing's side.
내가 훙징 쪽으로 갈게
Restrain yourself.
당신, 자제 좀 해
Come on, honey. Don't leave me behind.
아니, 여보 나 두고 가면 안 되지
-Honey. -What are you doing here?
- 여보 - 왜 따라와?
We each support one side.
각자 한 팀씩 응원하자고
You support our daughter,
당신은 딸 응원해
and I'll support our son's team.
난 저쪽 응원할 테니까
Mom. Mom.
엄마, 엄마
Take your lovestruck husband away.
사랑꾼 남편 좀 데리고 가요
Look at him.
마음이 이미
He is here, but his heart is over there.
콩밭에 가 있잖아요
I'm afraid he'll ruin Hengjiu's team spirit.
우리 헝주 팀 경기 분위기 흐릴까 봐 겁나요
Listen to your tone.
참 나
Honey,
여보
I'll go with you.
내가 같이 가줄게 같이 가
Be careful.
천천히 가
I won't. I absolutely won't...
난 절대로 안 흔들려
I will definitely stand firm
누나 때문에라도
for you.
내 입장 굳게 지킬 거야
[Invincible Yongchuan Hengjiu]
[융촨 헝주, 백전불패]
Come on, Hengjiu!
헝주 파이팅!
Go, go, go!
- 파이팅! 파이팅! 파이팅!
[Invincible Yongchuan Hengjiu]
[융촨 헝주, 백전불패]
-Come on, Hengjiu! -Go, go, go!
- 헝주 파이팅! - 파이팅!
Hongjing No. 8 High!
훙징 제8고!
Go, go, go!
- 파이팅! 파이팅! 파이팅!
Is there anyone you particularly want to cheer for today?
너 오늘 특별히 응원하고 싶은 사람 있어?
It must be Qin Ao.
당연히 친아오겠지
-No! That's not true! -Of course it's him.
- 아니거든? 그런 거 아니야 - 맞으면서 뭘 그래?
You're blushing.
너 얼굴 빨개졌다
No, I'm not.
아니라니까
Miss, can we switch seats?
학생, 자리 좀 바꿔줄 수 있을까?
Sure.
네
Great. Here.
잘됐네, 자
[Go For It]
[아자 아자]
And this one.
이것도 줄게
[Hold Your Head High, Hongjing's Pride]
[겸손 필요 없다 훙징의 자랑]
[Victory for Hongjing]
[훙징 필승]
Qi Liang's dad,
치량 아빠
you said you weren't coming.
전엔 안 온다더니
Look at how great the kids are.
애들 뛰는 것 좀 봐요 너무 멋지잖아요
Yeah.
그러네요
It's a good thing that they were given this chance.
그때 기회를 주길 정말 잘했어요
Later,
이따가
just cheer for them with all your might.
목청 터져라 응원하자고요
-Yeah. -Yeah. Cheer for them with all your might.
- 그래요 - 좋아요, 열심히 응원합시다
Okay! Come on!
- 네 - 파이팅!
Hongjing No. 8 High!
훙징 제8고!
Go, go, go!
- 파이팅! 파이팅! 파이팅!
Director Jin, what brings you here?
진 주임님 여긴 어쩐 일이세요?
Isn't this a school-wide event?
전교생 행사인데
What's wrong with me being here?
내가 오는 게 뭐가 이상해요?
You should have come earlier. Come on.
잘 오셨어요, 이리 오세요
Have a seat. Here's a flag.
여기 앉으세요 응원 깃발 받으시고
Come.
여기요
[Hongjing No. 8 High School]
[훙징 제8고]
[Yongchuan Hengjiu]
[융촨 헝주]
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League]
[융촨 유소년 슈퍼 리그]
[Hongjing No. 8 High School vs. Yongchuan Hengjiu]
[훙징 제8고 대 융촨 헝주]
-Hongjing No. 8 High! -Go! Go! Go!
- 훙징 제8고! - 파이팅! 파이팅! 파이팅!
Don't expect our team to go easy today.
우리 팀이 봐줄 거란 기대는 마
It's a battle of honor.
명예를 건 싸움이니까
Likewise.
나도 동감이야
A battle of honor?
명예를 좋아하네
You guys will definitely lose.
너희가 무조건 져
Are you so confident
설마 프릴 칼라 덕분에
because of the lace collar?
자신감이 생긴 건 아니죠?
Baby, hi.
완싱
Where are those kids?
그 녀석들 어디 있어?
Call them over.
좀 불러봐
I want to talk to them.
나 얘기 좀 하게
Ms. Ju is here to cheer for you.
샤오리 선생님이 응원 전화 오셨어
-Let's go. -Okay.
- 가자 - 좋아요
It's Ms. Ju.
쥐리 선생님이셔
Ms. Ju.
선생님
-Ms. Ju.
- 샤오리 선생님!
I have a performance today,
나 오늘 공연이 있어서
so I can't come to the game
현장에는
to cheer you on.
못 가지만
But you must win
너희 꼭 이겨야 해
and make us proud, understand?
절대 쫄지 말고, 알겠지?
Otherwise...
안 그러면…
[Microphone on] [Speaker on] [Camera off]
[마이크 켜짐] [스피커 켜짐][카메라 켜짐]
5 physics papers.
물리 시험지 5장 푼다
Seriously? Come on!
그걸 또 늘려요?
Then 10.
그럼 10장으로 하지, 뭐
-This is too much pressure. -How can you do this?
- 너무 빡빡하네 - 그런 게 어디 있어요?
-That's lame.
- 장난 아니네 - 그러면 재미없죠
-Alright. That's enough. -It's not fun at all.
- 됐어, 그만하고 - 진짜 재미없게 왜 이래요
Let's get ready.
이제 준비하자
Brothers,
얘들아
let's play to our heart's content!
오늘 아주 후회 없이 뛰어보자!
-To our heart's content!
- 무조건 후회 없이! - 후회 없이!
Wanxing, go ahead.
완싱, 얼른 가봐
Go for it!
파이팅! 파이팅! 파이팅!
Don't worry, Li.
걱정 마
Wait for our good news.
좋은 소식 기다려
We need a little ritual.
제대로 기분 내 보자
Come on, come on.
- 자, 모여 - 모여
Come on, come on!
- 이리 와
Captain.
주장
-Coach, Coach. Ms. Lin. -Coach.
- 코치님, 린 선생님 - 코치님
Hongjing No. 8 High!
훙징 제8고!
Let's go for it!
- 파이팅! 파이팅! 파이팅!
If you ask me,
있잖아
the Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team
훙징 제8고 팀은
will lose no matter who
어떤 코치가 와도
their coach is.
우리한테 안 돼
Hongjing is a respectable opponent.
훙징도 존중받아 마땅한 상대야
We shouldn't underestimate them.
방심하지 말자
What happened?
무슨 일 있었어?
Why the 180-degree change in attitude?
태도가 180도 바뀌었네
They deserve to be respected.
존중할 만한 라이벌이니까
Let's go all out!
우리도 최선을 다하자
Come on!
자
Yongchuan Hengjiu!
융촨 헝주!
We've got this!
- 파이팅!
Now it's time for the coin toss.
지금은 토스로 진영을 정하고 있네요
As the referee tosses the coin,
주심이 동전을 던지며
the final officially begins.
드디어 결승전의 막이 오릅니다
Hongjing No. 8 High and Yongchuan Hengjiu
훙징 제8고와 융촨 헝주는
have fought their way from the group stage to the final.
조별 리그부터 결승까지 쉼 없이 달려
Today they'll finally face each other again.
오늘 마침내 다시 결승 무대에서 만났습니다
It's a clash of old rivals.
피할 수 없는 승부!
This match
불꽃 튀는 경기가
is destined to be a thrilling encounter.
예상됩니다
Let's focus on the field
다들 그라운드로 눈을 돌려
and witness the crowning of the champion together.
우승팀의 탄생을 함께 지켜보시죠
Yongchuan, Yongchuan, march on to glory!
- 융촨, 거침없이 달려라!
Hongjing, Hongjing, make history!
- 훙징, 끝까지 가자!
Hengjiu's captain, No. 7 Fang Sulun, kicks off.
헝주의 주장 7번 팡쑤룬이 킥오프합니다
He passes to No. 10, Qin Qiechu.
10번 친체추에게 패스합니다
Qin Qiechu beats three players in a row!
친체추가 순식간에 세 명을 제치고
He reaches the edge of the box!
문전 앞까지 밀고 가는데
But the ball is intercepted
훙징의 15번
by Zheng Ren, Hongjing's No. 5.
정런이 공을 뺏어서
He dribbles the ball
드리블 치며
and moves forward.
그대로 전진합니다
Ms. Lin!
선생님
We didn't win the championship.
우린 우승이 아니에요
We will always be...
우린 영원한
runners-up.
준우승이에요
Lin Lu, you smart kid.
똘똘이 린루
I hope this time,
이번 경기에선
you won't finish second again.
더 이상 준우승이 아니길 바란다
Feng Suo.
펑쒀
♪ A starlit night ♪
♪ 밤하늘의 별빛 ♪
You are always the team's
넌 영원히 우리 팀의
most solid last line of defense.
가장 든든한 마지막 방어벽이야
♪ Secrets falling into my palm ♪
♪ 손바닥 위로 떨어진 은밀한 속삭임, 속삭임 ♪
Jianghe!
장허
♪ Unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ 수수께끼를 풀고 ♪
♪ It was you who gave me this brilliance ♪
♪ 내게 눈부신 빛을 선물한 건 너야, 바로 너 ♪
♪ Lasting memories ♪
♪ 기나긴 기억 ♪
♪ The distance that brings our dreams closer ♪
♪ 꿈과 가까워진 거리 그 거리 ♪
Hey.
학생
Don't you need to get a teacher's permission to borrow a football?
축구공 빌리려면 선생님께 말씀드려야 하잖아
♪ To run toward you ♪
♪ 너에게 달려가기 위해 ♪
What grade and class are you in?
몇 학년 몇 반이야?
♪ I keep practicing with no turning back ♪
♪ 난 거침없이 연습 또 연습해 ♪
What's your name?
이름은 뭐야?
I'm a senior in Class 5. My name is Qin Ao.
고3 5반 친아오예요
Qin as in Emperor Qin.
진시황의 '친'에
[100 free football equipment rentals]
[축구용품 100번 무료 대여 카드]
Ao as in Tibetan Mastiff, without the "dog" component.
사자개의 '야오'인데 개는 아니에요
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
This works.
빌릴 수 있다고
I'll lend you the ball.
축구공 빌려줄게
Really?
정말요?
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
Then who will sign it?
그럼 누가 서명해요?
It's fine. Again!
괜찮아, 다시
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
Chen Jianghe.
천장허
Your hard work
네 노력 덕분에
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 널 향해 달려가 ♪
makes the 100-use ball borrowing card
축구공 대여 카드 100회가
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 두려움 없이 앞으로 나아가 ♪
seem far from enough.
턱없이 부족해졌어
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪ 나란히 함께 ♪
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ 나 자신이 되어 ♪
Let's go!
가자
Come on!
자
♪ Amid the storm ♪
♪ 폭풍 속에서 ♪
♪ As our breaths slowly intertwine ♪
♪ 천천히 다가오는 숨결, 숨결 ♪
There!
저기
-Go, go, go! -Okay!
- 파이팅! - 좋아
♪ Heartbeats alternating ♪
♪ 교차하는 심장 소리 ♪
♪ A chemistry about to emerge ♪
♪ 터져 나올 듯한 호흡, 호흡 ♪
♪ The stars are shining ♪
♪ 반짝이는 별빛 ♪
♪ Take my hand and run forward ♪
♪ 내 손을 잡고 앞으로 달려, 달려 ♪
Pass it now!
빨리 패스해!
The person we've been waiting for is here.
우리가 기다리던 사람이 왔네요
A bunch of amateurs.
오합지졸을 모아 놓고
♪ For you ♪
♪ 널 위해서라면 ♪
You call yourselves football players?
무슨 축구를 해?
♪ I'm willing to keep practicing and practicing ♪
♪ 이렇게 몇 번이고 연습, 또 연습해 ♪
Get out of here.
당장 꺼져
Am I wrong?
내가 틀린 말 했어?
A bunch of losers.
실력도 없는 놈들
Wen Chengye.
원청예
Has it been a long time
지금의 넌
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
since you felt lonely?
외롭다는 생각 안 한 지 꽤 됐지?
Dad.
아빠
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
I'm not a stray dog.
전 들개가 아니에요
I've got friends.
저한테는 친구가 있어요
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
I know what I want to study.
제가 좋아하는 건 따로 있어요
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
Football—
전 축구를
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 널 향해 달려가 ♪
I will keep playing it.
계속할 거예요
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 두려움 없이 앞으로 나아가 ♪
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪ 나란히 함께 ♪
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ 나 자신이 되어 ♪
And you, Fu Xinshu.
그리고 너, 푸신수
Ms. Lin,
선생님
I don't have
저는 이번 생에
many chances left in this life.
더는 기회가 없을 거예요
I really love football.
저는 축구를 정말 좋아해요
So I don't want to give up.
그래서 포기하고 싶지 않아요
You truly deserve to be
훙징 제8고 축구팀 주장
the captain of Hongjing No. 8 High.
넌 자격이 충분해
The 23rd!
스물세 번째
Qin Ao!
친아오
Only those who have traveled far and wide
수많은 산을 넘어본 사람만이
will reach the hardest stretch of the journey.
가장 좁고 막힌 여정을 만나게 돼
You know very well
너도 알지?
♪ Regaining courage ♪
♪ 다시 용기를 내 ♪
that sometimes taking a step back
한 발 물러나면
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
can make the journey easier.
더 넓은 세상이 펼쳐진다는 걸
But when the coin is tossed
하지만 동전이 떨어지고
♪ Heartbeat's response ♪
♪ 두근거림으로 화답해 ♪
and the bell rings,
종소리가 울리면
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
you will still find yourself trapped on this narrow path.
넌 여전히 이 좁은 여정에 갇히게 될 거야
Because
왜냐하면
those who truly walk the narrow path
진정으로 좁은 길에 들어선 사람은
will never give up.
끝내 포기하지 못하거든
♪ Regaining courage ♪
♪ 다시 용기를 내 ♪
Behind you!
뒤로, 뒤로
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
Hengjiu's captain, Fang Sulun,
헝주 팀 주장 팡쑤룬이
passes the ball into the attacking half!
전방으로 패스하고
♪ Heartbeat's response ♪
♪ 두근거림으로 화답해 ♪
Qin Qiechu takes possession and breaks into the box!
친체추, 공을 받아 페널티 에어리어로 돌파합니다
Hongjing is in danger. He goes down!
위험하네요, 훙징! 넘어졌어요
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
-Here! -Penalty!
- 페널티킥 - 페널티킥이네요
The referee points to the penalty spot!
주심이 페널티 스폿을 가리킵니다
Okay.
좋아
That shouldn't have been a foul.
이게 어떻게 파울이에요?
-Hongjing's defense is caught out -Okay.
- 훙징 수비가 뚫리면 - 좋았어
and forced to commit a foul.
어쩔 수 없이 파울을 범하고
The referee awards Hengjiu a penalty.
주심이 헝주에 페널티킥을 선언합니다
The match has reached a critical moment.
경기가 결정적인 순간에 이르렀습니다
Hengjiu
헝주가
have been given a penalty that could change the course of the game.
판을 바꿀 수 있는 페널티킥을 얻어냅니다
Standing over the spot
페널티킥 지점에 선 선수는
is Hengjiu's star player,
헝주의 스타 플레이어
Qin Qiechu.
친체추입니다
Facing him
그를 상대할 선수는
is Hongjing's goalkeeper, Feng Suo.
훙징 제8고의 골키퍼 펑쒀입니다
At this moment,
엄청난 압박감이
the weight of the match rests squarely
지금 이 순간 온전히
on the shoulders of these two young players.
두 젊은 선수의 어깨에 달려 있습니다
I don't believe he'll score!
저 녀석이 넣을 리가 없어
Suo,
펑쒀
we're counting on you.
너만 믿는다
It doesn't matter if he scores.
골 먹혀도 괜찮아
We've still got time
아직 시간 있으니까
to turn things around.
역전할 수 있어
Stay calm.
침착해
Just like in training.
훈련할 때처럼
I can do this.
할 수 있어
Trust your instincts, Feng Suo.
네 직감을 믿어, 펑쒀
You've practiced this thousands of times.
이걸 위해 수천 번은 연습했잖아
Coach,
코치님
how do I save a penalty kick?
페널티킥은 어떻게 막아야 해요?
You must believe you'll save it
이 공을 막아낼 수 있다고 스스로를 믿어야 해
more than your opponent believes they'll score.
상대보다 더 굳게 믿는 거야
Forget everything
모든 걸 잊고
and bravely dive to one side!
용감하게 한쪽으로 몸을 날려
What a save!
멋진 선방입니다
Feng Suo saves Qin Qiechu's penalty
친체추가 찬 공을
and gathers the ball safely!
펑쒀가 단단히 품에 안았습니다
Under the immense pressure of the final,
결승전이라는 엄청난 압박 속에서
Feng Suo makes a priceless save.
펑쒀가 천금 같은 선방을 해냈습니다
The score is still 0-0.
스코어는 여전히 0 대 0
Both sides are still evenly matched.
양 팀 모두 같은 출발선에 서 있습니다
Come on!
파이팅!
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team]
[훙징 제8고등학교 축구팀]
[VIP]
[귀빈석]
[Come On!]
[돌진]
[Hold Your Head High, Hongjing's Pride]
[겸손 필요 없다 훙징의 자랑]
The match is now in the 88th minute.
현재 경기는 후반 88분을 향해 가고 있고요
Hongjing No. 8 High earns a corner kick.
훙징 제8고가 코너킥 기회를 얻습니다
It will be taken by their captain, No. 10, Fu Xinshu.
주장인 등번호 10번 푸신수가 찹니다
The corner kick is taken.
코너킥 올라갑니다
There's chaos in the box.
페널티 에어리어 안은 혼전 상황입니다
Qin Ao gets to the ball first! A header on goal!
친아오가 먼저 따내 헤더 슛!
Hengjiu's goalkeeper parries the ball,
헝주 골키퍼가 공을 쳐 냅니다
but the danger isn't over yet!
아직 위기는 끝나지 않았습니다
No. 11!
11번
No. 11, Wen Chengye, follows up with a shot!
11번 원청예의 추가 슈팅
Goal!
골인!
[Victory for Hongjing]
[훙징 필승]
♪ No matter how long the road ahead ♪
♪ 미래가 멀다 해도 ♪
[Hongjing No. 8 High School, Strong as a Dragon]
[훙징 제8고 용처럼 튼튼해]
♪ Nothing can stop me ♪
♪ 내 질주는 멈추지 않아 ♪
The game is over!
경기가 종료됐습니다
♪ Break through every haze of doubt ♪
♪ 모든 방황을 부수며 ♪
Hongjing No. 8 High are the champions!
훙징 제8고가 우승을 차지했어요
♪ Chase the light within me ♪
♪ 나만의 빛을 쫓아가 ♪
I think the charm of competitive sports
스포츠 경기의 매력은
♪ Strong wings grow through the storm ♪
♪ 풍파 속에서 끝내 강인한 날개를 펼칠 테니까 ♪
lies in the fact that everything is unknown.
모든 것이 미지수라는 점에 있는 것 같습니다
♪ Even if no one cheers ♪
♪ 모두가 날 외면해도 ♪
True warriors don't run on a smooth road,
진정한 용사는 탄탄대로를 달리는 것이 아니라
but break through the narrow paths.
좁은 길에서 포위망을 뚫는 것입니다
♪ I'll keep fighting my way through ♪
♪ 힘을 다해 싸울 거야 ♪
Dear audience,
시청자 여러분
♪ On a deserted battlefield ♪
♪ 아무도 없는 경기장에서 ♪
let's remember the names of these young men.
이 젊은 선수들의 이름을 기억해 주시기 바랍니다
♪ Thrive and bloom ♪
♪ 당당하게 성장해 ♪
They are:
바로
No. 11, Wen Chengye,
11번 원청예
[Come On!]
[돌진]
♪ I'll take every scar ♪
♪ 모든 상처를 ♪
No. 10, Fu Xinshu,
10번 푸신수
No. 9, Qin Ao,
9번 친아오
♪ As my badge of honor ♪
♪ 영광의 훈장으로 삼을 거야 ♪
No. 7, Chen Jianghe,
7번 천장허
[Go For It]
[아자 아자]
No. 6, Lin Lu,
6번 린루
No. 13, Zheng Feiyang,
13번 정페이양
No. 18, Qi Liang,
18번 치량
No. 23, Zhi Hui,
23번 즈후이
No. 1, Feng Suo,
1번 펑쒀
No. 5, Yu Ming,
5번 위밍
and No. 15, Zheng Ren!
15번 정런 선수입니다
♪ If braving the wind and waves ♪
♪ 거센 풍파를 용감하게 마주하는 것만이 ♪
They didn't retreat on the narrow paths,
그들은 곤란 앞에 물러서지 않았고
didn't fall apart in adversity,
역경 속에서도 흩어지지 않았으며
♪ Is what it takes to grow ♪
♪ 성장이라고 한다면 ♪
and didn't collapse under doubts.
의심 속에서도 쓰러지지 않았습니다
This is their
이것이 바로 그들의
sportsmanship!
스포츠 정신입니다
♪ I will stubbornly go against the current ♪
♪ 난 기꺼이 그곳에서 ♪
Everyone,
관중 여러분
let's meet again next year
내년에 다시 만나
♪ And let myself go wild ♪
♪ 뜨겁게 싸워 볼 거야 ♪
for another brilliant moment!
다음의 찬란함을 기약합시다!
♪ No matter how long the road ahead ♪
♪ 미래가 멀다 해도 ♪
♪ Nothing can stop me ♪
♪ 내 질주는 멈추지 않아 ♪
[One Year Later]
[1년 후]
♪ Break through every haze of doubt ♪
♪ 모든 방황을 부수며 ♪
♪ Chase the light within me ♪
♪ 나만의 빛을 쫓아가 ♪
We're almost there.
바로 앞이에요
[Sports Equipment Room]
[체육용품 보관실]
-Hello, Director.
- 안녕하세요, 주임 선생님 - 안녕하세요
Hello.
어, 그래
Come and take a look.
자, 한번 둘러봐요
This is our sports equipment room.
여기가 우리 체육용품 보관실이에요
Here are the keys.
열쇠, 여기 받으시고요
Okay.
네
This is your desk.
여기가 선생님 자리예요
Director Qian.
첸 주임님
I heard that the previous keeper
저희 전임 관리 담당자분이
was a woman who was the top student at Yongchuan University.
융촨 대학교 수석 졸업생이라면서요?
I heard during her tenure,
재직 기간에
not only did she lead our
훙징 축구팀을 데리고
Hongjing Football Team to the top of the league table,
우승을 차지한 건 물론이고
but now she's also applying for a Ph.D.
지금은 박사 과정까지 준비하신다고 들었어요
That shows
그러니까
our sports equipment room
우리 체육용품 보관실이
is a lucky place.
아주 명당이라는 겁니다
I wouldn't
아무나
bring just anyone here.
들어올 수 있는 곳이 아니에요
Okay, Director.
네, 주임님
I will definitely work hard.
꼭 열심히 하겠습니다
Alright, this is the rack for volleyballs.
그래요 이건 배구공 놓는 선반이고
And this shelf is all shuttlecocks.
이 칸은 전부 배드민턴공이에요
Let's look over here.
이쪽도 한번 봅시다
-This is... -This is the equipment supply room.
- 여긴... - 기구들을 모아둔 곳이죠
Alright?
네
[Lucky Gifts]
[행운의 리리]
♪ Dreams made of dazzling starlight ♪
♪ 눈부신 별빛으로 만든 꿈이 ♪
♪ Light up the sky ♪
♪ 하늘을 밝히고 ♪
♪ I run towards your world ♪
♪ 나는 너의 세계로 달려가 ♪
♪ With a gaze that mirrors yours ♪
♪ 너와 눈빛을 나란히 해 ♪
[Lucky Gifts]
[행운의 리리]
♪ The rainbow deep within your heart ♪
♪ 네 마음속 무지개가 되어 ♪
♪ Soaring atop the peak ♪
♪ 저 높은 정상을 가로지를 때 ♪
♪ I'm right here by your side ♪
♪ 나는 바로 네 곁에 있어 ♪
♪ My heart beats in time with yours ♪
♪ 내 마음도 너를 따라 뛰어 ♪
♪ Through twists and daring adventures ♪
♪ 굽이치는 길과 모험 속에서 ♪
♪ I'll help you embrace your transformation ♪
♪ 너를 위해 이 눈부신 변화를 이뤄내 ♪
♪ And guard all that makes you one of a kind ♪
♪ 너의 특별함을 지켜줄게 ♪
-He added a new one last time. -Pass the ball!
- 지난번에 새로 추가했어요 - 공 줘
-Pass. -What about mental health counseling now?
- 패스 - 심리 상담은 어떻게 됐나요?
We already have
이젠 전문적인
a professional mental health support plan in place.
심리 대응책이 있어요
Don't slack off.
게으름 피우지 말자
-And we've also brought in a team doctor. -Pass the ball.
- 팀 닥터도 찾았고요 - 공 줘
-Quicken your feet! -Don't worry.
- 보속 올려 - 걱정 마세요
-Our training programs -Pass.
- 지금은 훈련 중이에요 - 패스해
are tailored to the kids' condition.
애들 컨디션을 봐 가면서 하는 거죠
Pass the ball!
패스
-We've actually gone over budget. -Come on, pump your arms!
- 예산 초과인데요 - 자, 팔 움직여
-Those in the back! Your arms! -In fact, our training program
- 뒤에 팔 - 사실 우리가 훈련을
-is not bad. -Pass the ball!
- 아주 잘하거든요 - 패스
Is that so?
그래요?
Yes, it's actually very good.
네, 아주 괜찮아요
Okay.
알았어요
-Alright, let's leave it at that for now. -Okay.
- 그럼 이만 가볼게요 - 네
I'll catch up with you later.
나중에 다시 얘기해요
Okay.
네
He's finishing up soon.
쟤 금방 끝나요
Do you want to wait for him in the lounge?
휴게실 가서 먼저 기다릴래요?
No need. I'll watch him here.
아니에요, 여기서 좀 볼게요
-Let me see who is slacking off. -Okay.
- 누가 게으름 피우는지 보자 - 그래요
Why are you carrying so many materials?
무슨 자료를 그렇게 많이 들고 있어요?
These are the upgraded plans for the youth academy.
이건 유소년 팀 커리큘럼 개혁 방안이에요
He said that besides technique,
왕파가 그러는데 기술적인 부분 외에
mental health is also very important.
정신 건강도 아주 중요하대요
Not bad.
잘했어
Pass the ball.
패스
That's very thoughtful.
정말 세심하게 생각했네요
By the way,
참
are you guys preparing
지금 산간 지역 공익 훈련 캠프
a charity training camp in the mountains?
준비 중이시라면서요?
Yes, I'm going the week after next.
맞아요, 다다음 주에 가요
You know Wang Fa.
왕파 고집 알잖아요
He's continuing to offer free spots.
계속 무료 정원을 열어두고 싶어 해요
He thinks no talent
좋은 유망주를 한 명도
should be buried.
묻히게 해선 안 된다면서요
The only problem is...
다만 딱 하나
that...
문제라면…
I'm under a little pressure.
제가 스트레스를 너무 받아요
The budget is too high,
예산이 너무 세서
and the financial pressure is immense.
자금 압박이 장난 아니거든요
No wonder.
어쩐지
You look like you're going a little bald.
보니까 머리가 좀 벗겨지신 것 같은데요?
Not at all!
무슨 소리예요
My hairline isn't receding at all.
내 앞머리가 어디가 벗겨졌다고 그래요?
I'm telling you, I've had thick hair since I was a kid.
나 원래 태어날 때부터 숱 많았어요
If you call this little hair,
내 머리가 적은 거면
then what about bald people?
대머리들은 세상 어떻게 살아요?
Tian...
언니는
still hasn't accepted you?
아직도 안 받아줘요?
Well...
그게 말이죠
She said
나랑 왕파가
she'd only let me take up her time after Wang Fa
이 훈련 학교를 제대로 궤도에 올려놓으면
and I had run the training school well.
그때 자기 시간 내주겠대요
Congratulations.
축하해요
That means she's finally coming around.
그 정도면 승낙한 거나 다름없네요
Halfway there, I guess.
절반은 넘어온 셈이죠
But you're right.
린 선생님 말이 맞았어요
If I'm excellent enough, she'll see it.
내가 먼저 멋진 사람이 되면 누나도 알아봐 주더라고요
Right?
그렇죠?
I plan to, after everything is done,
이 일 다 끝나면 자동차 여행이나 떠나서
take a road trip to relax
푹 쉬려고요
and clear my mind.
마음도 좀 정리하고요
You? Driving?
직접 운전하게요?
Are you sure you won't get lost once on the road?
출발하자마자 길 잃어버리실 텐데요
-I… -Don't worry.
- 나 참 - 걱정 마
I had someone make a special navigation system for you.
내가 맞춤형 네비게이션을 준비해 뒀거든
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이야?
Just in time.
마침 잘 왔네
Mr. Principal,
교장 선생님
please work overtime
야근 좀 하셔야겠어요
and finalize these plans.
이 기획안들 결재 좀 해주세요
I can't do it today.
오늘은 안 돼
I'll do it tomorrow morning.
내일 아침에 하자
Let's go.
가요
Tomorrow?
내일 아침이라니
Wait.
아니
Tomorrow is Saturday!
내일 토요일이잖아
You are exploiting your employee!
악덕 업주 같으니라고
Tell me.
빨리 말해봐요
What trick did you pull with his navigation?
네비게이션에 무슨 음모를 꾸민 거예요?
I did some special processing to the voice
네비 안내 음성을 특별하게 설정했거든요
and changed it into Wang Tian's voice.
우리 누나 목소리로 바꿨어요
With my sister's sarcasm,
누나의 잔소리랑 비아냥이 나오면
he definitely won't get lost easily.
절대 길 잃을 일 없을 거예요
Use one evil to fight another?
이독제독이네요
Good idea.
좋은 생각이에요
Want to go in and have a look?
안에 들어가 볼래요?
Maybe there's a surprise.
어쩌면 깜짝 선물이 있을지도 모르잖아요
Is this...
이게 뭐예요?
[Happy Birthday]
[생일 축하]
Is this the surprise you were talking about?
이게 당신이 말한 깜짝 선물이에요?
[Ms. Lin, Happy birthday]
[린 선생님, 생일 축하해요]
Surprise!
- 서프라이즈!
You startled me.
깜짝이야
What brings you here?
너희가 여기 어쩐 일이야?
To celebrate your birthday.
선생님 생일 축하해 드리려고 왔죠
Did you prepare all this?
이거 다 너희가 준비한 거야?
Thank you.
고마워
Ms. Lin, happy birthday!
린 선생님, 생일 축하드려요
We wish you a successful return to Yongchuan
융촨으로 복귀하여
and hope you take back everything you lost!
빼앗긴 모든 걸 되찾아 오시길 바랄게요
Thank you.
고마워, 애들아
But am I some female version of Edmond Dantès?
근데 내가 무슨 몬테크리스토 백작 부인이라도 되니?
Just kidding.
농담이에요, 농담
I grilled all these just now.
이거 제가 막 구운 거예요
I have more ingredients over there.
저쪽에 더 있으니까
I'll go grill some more.
가서 좀 더 챙겨올게요
Coach, here. Have some milk.
코치님, 우유 드세요
Where is Chen Jianghe?
천장허는 어디 갔어?
Didn't you say he was coming with you?
너희랑 같이 온다고 하지 않았니?
Don't mention him.
말도 마세요
He booked the high-speed rail ticket
기차표까지 다 끊어놨는데
but was temporarily dragged away by his teacher.
갑자기 교수님한테 붙잡혔대요
He had no choice.
어쩔 수 없죠
The sports university suddenly had an event,
체대에 갑자기 행사가 잡혔는데
and they were short on staff.
일손이 부족해서
The whole student union had to go.
학생회 애들은 다 강제 동원됐거든요
But
대신
he told me to wish you
장허가 꼭 전해달래요
a happy birthday.
린 선생님 생일 축하드린다고요
I should thank him too.
알았어, 고맙다고 전해줘
I understand.
다 이해해
These kids are so outstanding now.
애들이 이렇게 멋지게 잘 커 줬는데
[Ms. Lin, Happy birthday]
[린 선생님, 생일 축하해요]
Why don't you bribe them
차라리 매수해서
and recruit them to work at your school?
당신 학교로 스카우트하는 건 어때요?
That's a good idea.
그거 좋은 생각이네요
No, no.
아니에요
No need to bribe us at all.
매수할 필요도 없어요
We'd be happy to do that.
저흰 언제든 좋아요
Right, although they aren't here in person,
참, 애들이 오진 못했지만
all their gifts are here.
선물은 다 보냈거든요
[Happy Birthday]
[생일 축하]
This one is from Zhi Hui.
이건 즈후이 거고요
And Yu Ming, Zheng Ren, Jiang...
위밍, 정런, 장…
Right, this one.
참, 이거
This is the most important one.
이게 제일 중요해요
We wrote this ourselves.
저희가 직접 쓴 편지거든요
[Ms. Lin: May you live a long and happy life, stay 18 forever, shine with endless beauty,]
[린 선생님, 오래오래 건강하시고 매년 18세 미모 유지하시길]
So many idioms?
덕담을 아주 쏟아부었네
[be dazzling in every way, enjoy lasting health and happiness, smile like a flower,]
[눈부신 미모, 만복을 누리시고 늘 웃음꽃만 피어나시길]
[stay full of energy, and have a very happy birthday!]
[건강하세요, 생일 축하해요!]
[By the handsome guys from Hongjing No. 8 High School]
[멋쟁이 훙징 제8고 일동]
That's very thoughtful of you.
감동이다
Thank you.
고마워
The beef is here.
소고기 대령입니다
[Happy Birthday]
[생일 축하]
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
let me tell you, this beef
이 소고기로 말씀드릴 것 같으면
is very special.
아주 특별한 고기입니다
Zheng Feiyang had it flown in from Shandong.
정페이양이 산동에서 공수해 온
It's beef from southwestern Shandong yellow cattle.
프리미엄 소고기예요
It's super tender.
진짜 입에서 녹아요
A birthday gift for you.
생일 선물입니다
Tell him thank you.
페이양한테도 고맙다고 전해줘
What is he up to lately?
걔는 요즘 뭐 하고 지내니?
That kid is doing great.
그 자식 요즘 엄청 잘 나가요
Whenever he has no classes, he goes shop-hopping as a vlogger.
수업 없을 땐 맛집 탐방 블로거로 활동하는데요
He has a ton of followers.
팔로워가 장난 아니에요
[Happy Birthday]
[생일 축하]
A vlogger?
블로거라고?
Then I have to take a picture of him for my content.
그럼 나도 사진 찍어서 소스로 쓰라고 보내줘야겠네
Sorry I'm late.
죄송합니다, 제가 늦었네요
Wen Chengye? Aren't you in the US?
원청예! 너 미국에 있는 거 아니었어?
Spring break.
봄 방학이라서요
Thank you
고맙다
-To celebrate my birthday, you came... -You think too much.
- 내 생일 때문에 이렇게까지... - 아니에요
I was planning to come back for spring break anyway.
어차피 국내로 휴가 올 계획이었어요
You haven't changed a bit.
여전하구나
Indeed.
그러게요
The ugly face of a capitalist.
악덕 자본가 같은 삐딱한 태도에
I just came back,
귀국하자마자
-and you have started... -What?
- 태클이냐? - 뭐 어쩌라고?
What about it?
덤벼 봐, 덤벼 봐
Captain, how does your first year of college feel?
주장 대학 새내기 생활은 어때?
Not bad.
괜찮아요
There's not much pressure at Hongjing Normal University anyway.
어차피 훙징 사범대는 학업 압박이 별로 없어서
We'll see when we start job hunting after graduation.
졸업하고 취업할 걱정이나 해야죠
Ms. Lin, Coach, have a seat.
자, 선생님, 코치님 앉으세요
Have a seat.
앉아요
Lu.
린루야
Lu?
린루?
Boss! Boss!
대장, 대장!
Have you seen Ms. Lin?
린 선생님 만났어?
-Lu, long time no see. -Ms. Lin!
- 린루, 오랜만이야 - 린 선생님
[Skipping Work to Celebrate a Birthday. Unfollow Me If You Must]
[휴방하고 생일 축하 팔로워 떨어져도 감수함]
I miss you so much!
선생님 정말 너무 보고 싶어요
Happy birthday!
생일 축하드립니다
Thank you.
그래, 고마워
What does the title
너 근데 라방에 제목에
[Skipping Work to Celebrate a Birthday. Unfollow Me If You Must]
[휴방하고 생일 축하 팔로워 떨어져도 감수함]
of your livestream mean?
뭐라고 써 놓은 거니?
Skipping work to celebrate a birthday.
휴방하고 생일 축하
Unfollow me if you must?
팔로워 떨어져도 감수함
Keep a low profile.
별거 아니에요
[Skipping Work to Celebrate a Birthday. Unfollow Me If You Must]
[휴방하고 생일 축하 팔로워 떨어져도 감수함]
I haven't reached my streaming hours this month.
제가 이번 달 방송 시간 채워야 하거든요
Let me just stay live and rack up some hours.
그냥 켜놓고 묻어가는 중이에요
Do you need me to play for you?
아니면 내가 대신 게임 해줄까?
Ms. Lin, your skills are too good.
선생님은 실력이 너무 좋으시잖아요
Everyone in my stream knows I suck.
제 방 팬들은 제가 똥손인 거 다 알아서
[Skipping Work to Celebrate a Birthday. Unfollow Me If You Must]
[휴방하고 생일 축하 팔로워 떨어져도 감수함]
They'd expose me in a second.
바로 1초 만에 들통나요
Ms. Lin, are you and Coach doing well lately?
선생님이랑 코치님 요즘 잘 지내시죠?
I'll definitely visit you once I'm done with work.
저 이거 바쁜 것만 끝나면 꼭 찾아뵐게요
Okay.
그래
Is this delicious, Coach?
그거 맛있어요, 코치님?
Yes.
맛있어
Zheng Feiyang sent it.
정페이양이 보낸 거야
Let's play together when you come back.
나중에 너 오면 같이 게임 한판 하자
[Skipping Work to Celebrate a Birthday. Unfollow Me If You Must]
[휴방하고 생일 축하 팔로워 떨어져도 감수함]
Please carry me!
꼭 좀 묻어가게 해주세요
By the way, Boss.
참, 대장
What is it?
뭔데?
This new gaming chair I bought is super comfortable.
나 최근에 새로 산 게이밍 의자가 진짜 편하거든
[Fun-to-Watch Streamer] [Peak King Lu]
[노답 비제이][정점의 루왕]
You must try it when you're here.
나중에 오면 꼭 앉아봐
Okay.
그래, 알았어
Hello.
안녕
Can I try it out?
나도 앉아 봐도 돼?
Okay, okay. No problem!
그럼, 당연하지
Alright, that's enough.
됐어
I'll add everyone to a group chat later.
이따가 내가 단톡방에 초대할 테니까
Just join it,
들어와서
and then we can hop on a call together.
다 같이 영상 통화하자
I'm hanging up now.
끊는다
Turn off that beauty filter. It looks terrible.
필터 좀 꺼, 징그러우니까
Okay, no problem.
그래, 알았어
Bye-bye.
끊어
Stop talking and eat up.
잔말 말고 얼른 먹자
-Ms. Lin. -Okay. Let me see.
- 린 선생님 - 어디 봐봐요
I've added them all to the group chat.
내가 애들 전부 초대했어요 들어와요
I'll go bring out the cake.
난 케이크 가져올게
I'll connect. You turn it on.
내가 연결할게, 네가 켜
I'll turn it on.
컴퓨터 좀 켤게요
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
Happy birthday!
생일 축하드려요
Thank you.
고마워
It's connected!
연결됐다
Does it work?
잘 보여?
Wait a minute.
잠깐만
You need to wait a minute.
조금만 기다려 봐
Hello, Ms. Lin! Hello, Coach!
린 선생님, 코치님 안녕하세요!
[Microphone on] [Speaker on] [Camera off]
[마이크 켜짐][스피커 켜짐] [카메라 켜짐]
Coach, can you hear me?
코치님, 제 목소리 들리세요?
-Stop! -Can you hear me?
- 잠깐만 - 잘 들려요?
Stop!
잠깐만!
[Microphone on] [Speaker on] [Camera off]
[마이크 켜짐][스피커 켜짐] [카메라 켜짐]
One at a time.
한 사람씩 얘기해
No rush.
급할 거 없어
Me first.
내가 먼저 할게
Happy birthday, Ms. Lin.
린 선생님, 생일 축하드려요
Thank you.
고마워
Did you get the southwestern Shandong yellow cattle beef I sent you?
제가 보낸 프리미엄 소고기 잘 받았어요?
It was flown to you,
비행기 태워서 보낸 보람이 있어야 하는데
so it's super fresh.
완전 신선하니까요
Don't let Qin Ao steal it.
친아오한테 다 뺏기면 안 돼요
Don't worry, Coach already ate it.
걱정 마, 이미 코치님 배 속으로 들어갔어
I ate it.
내가 다 먹었어
Then I'm relieved.
코치님이 드셨다니 다행이네요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
thank you for helping me find the courage to face life.
세상을 당당하게 마주할 용기를 주셔서 감사해요
Thank you for being so supportive
선생님은 저희가 가장 바닥에 있을 때
when we were at our lowest.
손 내밀어 이끌어주신 분이에요
You are a miracle in our lives.
선생님은 저희 삶의 기적입니다
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
Thank you for being with us.
함께해 주셔서 정말 감사했어요
♪ Time's passing by ♪
♪ 세월은 물처럼 ♪
I always wish
저는요
♪ Nothing remains ♪
♪ 흔적도 없이 흘러가고 ♪
I had met you earlier.
선생님을 더 일찍 만났더라면 얼마나 좋을까 싶어요
♪ All the dreamers awake alone ♪
♪ 함께 꿈꾸던 우리 쉽사리 잠들지 못하네 ♪
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
감사합니다, 린 선생님
Ms. Lin!
린 선생님
♪ Shadows above ♪
♪ 때로는 먹구름이 드리우고 ♪
I hope you get prettier and prettier
점점 더 예뻐지시고요
and stay happy every day.
매일매일 행복하세요
♪ Rain falls around ♪
♪ 축축한 빗물이 삶의 구석구석을 적셔도 ♪
Happy birthday!
생일 축하드려요
♪ In your arms ♪
♪ 네 품 안에서 ♪
Thank you
고맙습니다
♪ We become one ♪
♪ 평행하던 우리 세상은 마침내 하나가 돼 ♪
for helping me find the courage to face difficulties.
어려움에 맞설 용기를 가르쳐 주셔서요
♪ Through day and night ♪
♪ 낮과 밤이 흘러도 ♪
I will never forget what you said.
선생님께서 하신 말씀 평생 잊지 않을게요
♪ I can see you ♪
♪ 너의 눈동자 속에서 ♪
Happy birthday to you.
생일 축하드립니다
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
♪ In my eyes ♪
♪ 진짜 나를 마주해 ♪
thank you
정말 감사합니다
for helping me find the most important thing
제 인생에서
♪ Just hold me tight ♪
♪ 꼭 안아 주기만 하면 ♪
in my life
가장 소중한 것을 찾게 해주시고
♪ Look into my soul so deeply ♪
♪ 너의 시선은 내 영혼 깊숙이 닿아 ♪
and learn how to cherish it.
그것을 소중히 여기는 법을 알게 해주셔서요
Thank you.
고맙습니다
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
♪ Rainbow sunlight ♪
♪ 무지갯빛 후광 아래 ♪
happy birthday.
생일 축하드려요
[Campus Football Highlights]
[축구 개혁 발전 총체 방안]
Thank you for telling me
저도 괜찮은 아이라는 걸
♪ Painful tears are gone ♪
♪ 아픈 지난날은 어제가 되고 ♪
♪ Wonderful days ♪
♪ 반짝이는 아름다운 꿈은 ♪
that I'm not bad.
알려주셔서 정말 감사해요
♪ Are so close to me ♪
♪ 내게는 닿을 수 없는 것 같지만 ♪
I hope you and Coach have a happy marriage
코치님이랑 꼭 백년해로하세요
♪ Memories fly ♪
♪ 추억은 스쳐 가는 한숨처럼 ♪
[Campus Football Highlights]
[축구 개혁 발전 총체 방안]
♪ Leave them all behind ♪
♪ 지난 상처를 다정히 어루만지고 ♪
and have a baby soon.
얼른 예쁜 아기도 낳으시고요
Thank you.
선생님, 감사합니다
♪ Just take my hand and stay with me ♪
♪ 우리는 손을 맞잡은 채 영원히 함께해 ♪
Actually, I always imagined how great
전 맨날 그런 생각을 해요
it would have been if I had met you in my freshman year.
고1 때 선생님을 알았더라면 좋았을 거라고요
Then I wouldn't have been so timid
그랬다면 제가 이렇게 소심하지도
and lost.
이렇게 방황하지도 않았을 거예요
Thank you.
감사합니다
It was you who made me see my future clearly.
선생님 덕분에 미래의 방향을 제대로 알게 됐어요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
♪ Rainbow sunlight ♪
♪ 무지갯빛 후광 아래 ♪
happy birthday!
생일 축하드려요
Although I am not the best student you have had,
제가 선생님께서 가르치신 최고의 학생은 아닐지라도
♪ Painful tears are gone ♪
♪ 아픈 지난날은 어제가 되고 ♪
you are definitely the best teacher I have ever had.
선생님은 제가 뵌 최고의 선생님이십니다
♪ Wonderful days ♪
♪ 반짝이는 아름다운 꿈은 ♪
♪ Are so close to me ♪
♪ 내게는 닿을 수 없는 것 같지만 ♪
Let's put it this way.
뭐랄까요?
When I see dried radish,
지금도 무말랭이를 보면
I think of the Robert's Rules of Order
선생님이 가르쳐 주신
♪ Memories fly ♪
♪ 추억은 스쳐 가는 한숨처럼 ♪
you taught us.
로버트 의사 규칙이 생각나요
♪ Leave them all behind ♪
♪ 지난 상처를 다정히 어루만지고 ♪
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
감사합니다, 린 선생님
♪ Just take my hand and stay with me ♪
♪ 우리는 손을 맞잡은 채 영원히 함께해 ♪
You filled my high school years
제 고등학교 시절에
with so many wonderful memories.
아름다운 추억을 많이 만들어 주셔서요
♪ Rainbow sunlight ♪
♪ 무지갯빛 후광 아래 ♪
♪ Painful tears are gone ♪
♪ 아픈 지난날은 어제가 되고 ♪
Ms. Lin!
린선생님
♪ Wonderful days ♪
♪ 반짝이는 아름다운 꿈은 ♪
You dida-dida me, I huala-huala you!
- 가르쳐 주신 은혜 꼭 보답하겠습니다
♪ Are so close to me ♪
♪ 내게는 닿을 수 없는 것 같지만 ♪
♪ Memories fly ♪
♪ 추억은 스쳐 가는 한숨처럼 ♪
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
- 린 선생님, 감사합니다
♪ Leave them all behind ♪
♪ 지난 상처를 다정히 어루만지고 ♪
Brothers,
얘들아
Let's sing Happy Birthday
우리 린 선생님께
♪ Just take my hand and stay with me ♪
♪ 우리는 손을 맞잡은 채 영원히 함께해 ♪
to Ms. Lin together.
다 같이 생일 축하 노래 불러주자
-Okay.
- 그래 - 좋아
Three, two, one, go!
셋, 둘, 하나, 가자
Happy birthday to you.
생일 축하합니다
♪ Waiting for a dark cloud to pass by you ♪
♪ 먹구름 한 조각이 네 곁을 지나갈 때 ♪
♪ Listen closely to its cries ♪
♪ 그 울음소리에 귀 기울여 봐 ♪
♪ The heavy rain will wash away your reflection ♪
♪ 장대비가 네 그림자를 데려가 ♪
-Hurry up! -Coming.
- 빨리 와 - 알았어
Take a picture for me.
사진 좀 찍어줘
♪ And carry it toward distant scenery ♪
♪ 먼 곳의 풍경을 찾아 떠날 거야 ♪
[Graduation Ceremony]
[졸업식]
♪ Every experience has its meaning ♪
♪ 모든 경험에는 저마다의 의미가 있어 ♪
[Graduation Season—Forever Young]
[졸업 시즌 끝나지 않는 청춘]
♪ Scene by scene, they come together to form who I am ♪
♪ 장면 하나하나가 모여 지금의 나를 이루지 ♪
♪ Even the wounds that leave behind their marks ♪
♪ 상처가 흉터로 남는다 해도 ♪
♪ Have taught me how to heal myself ♪
♪ 날 치유하는 법을 배웠어 ♪
♪ The love I have given, the love I have received ♪
♪ 내가 준 사랑 내가 받은 사랑 ♪
♪ Every one of them gives me the strength not to fear being hurt ♪
♪ 그 모든 게 날 강하게 해 ♪
♪ Let my tears be carried away, back into the ocean ♪
♪ 내 눈물을 바다로 흘려보내 ♪
♪ And blown toward flowers blooming far away ♪
♪ 저 멀리 꽃 피는 곳으로 불어가 ♪
♪ I fill the blank spaces of life with colors ♪
♪ 빈 마음을 색으로 채워 가 ♪
♪ My dreams are not afraid to awaken; they continue to exist ♪
♪ 내 꿈은 깨어나도 사라지지 않아 ♪
♪ I go beyond the dark clouds and feel the haze disperse ♪
♪ 먹구름 너머 걷히는 하늘을 느껴 봐 ♪
♪ Let me understand myself more clearly ♪
♪ 날 더 잘 알게 될 테니까♪
[Wen Chengye]
[원청예]
♪ Every experience has its meaning ♪
♪ 모든 경험에는 저마다의 의미가 있어 ♪
[Wen Chengye] [Fu Xinshu]
[원청예][푸신수]
♪ Scene by scene, they come together to form who I am ♪
♪ 장면 하나하나가 모여 지금의 나를 이루지 ♪
♪ Even the wounds that leave behind their marks ♪
♪ 상처가 흉터로 남는다 해도 ♪
♪ Have taught me how to heal myself ♪
♪ 날 치유하는 법을 배웠어 ♪
♪ The love I have given, the love I have received ♪
♪ 내가 준 사랑 내가 받은 사랑 ♪
[Graduation Ceremony]
[졸업식]
♪ Every one of them gives me the strength not to fear being hurt ♪
♪ 그 모든 게 날 강하게 해 ♪
♪ Let my tears be carried away, back into the ocean ♪
♪ 내 눈물을 바다로 흘려보내 ♪
♪ And blown toward flowers blooming far away ♪
♪ 저 멀리 꽃 피는 곳으로 불어가 ♪
Stand there. Don't move.
저기, 저기 서
♪ I fill the blank spaces of life with colors ♪
♪ 빈 마음을 색으로 채워 가 ♪
♪ My dreams are not afraid to awaken; they continue to exist ♪
♪ 내 꿈은 깨어나도 사라지지 않아 ♪
What are you doing?
왜 그래?
You guys are the noisiest.
너희가 제일 시끄러워
-Be careful. -Exactly.
천천히 좀 해
You guys are the noisiest.
너희가 제일 시끄럽다고
-They are the noisiest. -Come on!
- 얘네 둘이 제일 시끄러워 - 나 진짜…
♪ I go beyond the dark clouds and feel the haze disperse ♪
♪ 먹구름 너머 걷히는 하늘을 느껴 봐 ♪
We can't even find you!
아니, 너희 보이지도 않더라?
Let's take a group photo of our football team.
우리 축구팀 단체 사진 찍자
Come on.
- 그래 - 찍어
I'll hold it. Take your time.
내가 들게, 서두르지 마
Do you know how to do it?
잘 찍을 수 있어?
Get down!
몸 낮춰
♪ Let me understand myself more clearly ♪
♪ 나를 더 잘 알게 될 테니까 ♪
-Get down, get down. -Get down.
- 좀 더 - 좀 더 낮춰
Jianghe is out of the frame.
장허도 없잖아
-Seriously. -Jianghe, Jianghe.
- 진짜 - 장허, 장허
-Okay. -There's a bee here!
- 됐어 - 여기 벌이 있어
♪ Take away my reflection ♪
♪ 내 그림자를 데려가 ♪
Come on.
왜 이래?
Hurry up. You're actually afraid of this?
빨리 좀 해, 뭐가 무서워?
♪ And carry it toward distant scenery ♪
♪ 먼 곳의 풍경을 찾아 떠날 거야 ♪
-Happy graduation!
- 졸업 축하해
Hold on, hold on.
잠깐만, 잠깐만
-For the graduation… -Where are Ms. Lin and Coach?
- 졸업이니까… - 린 선생님이랑 코치님은?
They're not here yet?
아직 안 오셨어?
Just call them.
전화하면 되잖아
Call them.
전화해
Make a video call.
영상 통화하자
A video call.
영상 통화
-Coach!
코치님, 코치님
Come on, Coach, what time is it?
아니, 코치님 지금이 몇 시인데
Why aren't you here yet?
왜 아직 안 오세요?
Got it.
알았어
To my students.
사랑하는 나의 제자들에게
I joined Hongjing No. 8 High School last year.
난 작년에 훙징 8중에 들어왔다
When I stood at the door of the Sports Equipment Room,
처음 체육용품 보관실 문 앞에 섰을 때만 해도
[Sports Equipment Room]
[체육용품 보관실]
I never thought
내가 이토록 깊숙이
that I would become so deeply involved
타인의 인생 여정에
in other people's journeys through life.
동참하게 될 줄은 꿈에도 몰랐어
Back then, trapped by my own painful fate,
그 당시 나는 비참한 운명에 갇혀
I knew that the hardest thing to overcome
세상에서 가장 이기기 힘든 적은
was the struggle within one's own heart.
바로 내 마음속 딜레마라는 걸 뼈저리게 느끼고 있었다
Like everyone else,
나 역시 다른 이들과 마찬가지로
I longed to witness an unstoppable dark horse rise.
거침없는 흑마의 질주를 기대했고
I hoped to find, in your stories,
너희의 이야기 속에서
the meaning that would help me keep going.
끝까지 버텨낼 의미를 찾길 바랐어
Later,
시간이 흐른 뒤에야
I realized
나는 깨달았어
that the hardest part of life
인생에서 가장 어려운 것은
is not the momentary decision to set out on a journey,
출발할 때의 한순간의 결심이 아니라
but the lasting willpower needed to keep climbing toward the peak.
정상을 향해 나아가는 끈질긴 집념이라는 것을
[Feng Suo] [Play football with the brothers]
[펑쒀 친구들과 함께 축구하기]
The greatest pain
인생에서 가장 쓴 고통은
is not gritting your teeth after falling off a cliff,
절벽 아래로 떨어진 후 이 악물고 버티는 순간이 아니라
[But what I want most in the end]
[마지막으로 원하는 건]
[is to win the championship with the guys] [Yu Ming]
[다 함께 우승을 차지하는 것 위밍]
but facing yourself and
내 마음에 물어
[Win the championship] [Chen Jianghe]
[우승 하기, 천장허]
making the choice that stays true to your conscience.
양심에 가장 부끄럽지 않은 선택을 내리는 순간이라는 것을
[Qin Ao] [I want to win the championship]
[친아오, 우승하고 싶다]
Education
교육은
has never been about me teaching you.
내가 너희에게 일방적으로 베푼 가르침이 아니었어
It has always been about us, teachers and students,
그건 우리 스승과 제자가
helping each other
서로를 붙잡아주고
and growing together.
함께 성장해 나가는 과정이었지
[1 day until the evil monthly exam]
[지독한 월간 고사 D-1]
The Olympic spirit
올림픽 정신은
is about being faster, higher, and stronger.
'더 빠르게, 더 높게 더 강하게'를 말하지만
And you have taught me
너희는 내게 또 다른 진리를 보여주었어
that through physical training
몸의 단련을 추구하고
and the pursuit of the limits of willpower,
의지의 한계에 도전할 때
the boundaries of the soul
우리 영혼의 영역 또한
can expand and grow wider
고난 속에서
amid hardship.
더욱 넓고 단단해진다는 것을
Adults always say
어른들은 늘 이렇게 말하지
that when you grow up, you will find
너희가 자라면 세상의 길은
the road ahead becoming wider and wider.
점점 더 넓어질 거라고
But unease and confusion,
하지만 불안과 방황
pain and hesitation,
고통과 미망
extreme hardships,
극단적인 곤경과
and difficult choices
시비를 가리는 양심의 고문은
have always been narrow paths
언제나 아주 소수의 사람만이
that few people ever manage to walk through.
겨우 지나갈 수 있는 좁디좁은 외나무다리 길이야
Real life
진짜 인생은
is bitter and long.
쓰고도 길어
Persevering to the end
끝까지 버틴다고 해서
may not always lead to a bright future.
반드시 넓은 세상이 열리는 것도 아니고
So,
그러니 때로는
it's okay
도망쳐도
to run away.
괜찮아
But I have always hoped that you would
하지만 난 너희가 언제나
have free will and independent minds.
자유로운 의지와 독립된 인격을 갖추기를 바란다
I hope you will learn how to live,
삶을 배우고
come to terms with yourselves,
스스로와 화해하며
discover what you love,
좋아하는 것을 발견하고
and have the courage to pursue it.
용기 있게 쫓아가기를 바란다
I hope you will always fight
너희가 매 순간
against the timid side of human nature,
내면의 나약함과 당당히 싸워 이기기를
live with courage,
용기로 가득 차기를
and always
그리고 언제나 나에게
give me the strength to seek understanding
절망 속에서도 깨달음을 얻는
even in moments of despair.
힘을 주기를 바란다
[Strive to ensure that the people experience]
[모든 사법 사건에서]
[fairness and justice in every judicial case.]
[공정과 정의를 느낄 수 있도록 노력하겠습니다]
And more than anything, I hope
그리고 내가 진정으로 바라는 것은
that I, too,
나 자신 또한
can become
내가 되고 싶었던
the person I aspire to be.
그 모습의 어른이 되는 것이다
Today, you no longer
지금의 너희는
need to read these meaningless words.
더 이상 이런 쓸데없는 글귀를 들춰보지 않아도 좋아
Yet, as you graduate,
하지만 졸업을 앞두고
I still want to offer my blessings for the journey ahead,
난 여전히 너희의 앞날을 축복하고 싶다
hoping that no matter how narrow the road may seem,
힘든 길을 걷게 되더라도
you will eventually find the light.
끝내 눈부신 광명을 맞이하기를
[Yet, as you graduate, I still want to offer my blessings for the journey ahead,]
[하지만 졸업을 앞두고 난 여전히 너희의 앞날을 축복하고 싶다]
[hoping that no matter how narrow the road may seem, you will eventually find the light.]
[힘든 길을 걷게 되더라도 끝내 눈부신 광명을 맞이하기를]
[Yongchuan University]
[융촨 대학교]
The human spirit
인간의 마음은
♪ A starlit night ♪
♪ 밤하늘의 별빛 ♪
is like a seed hidden beneath the soil.
흙 속에 숨겨진 씨앗과도 같다
♪ Secrets falling into my palm ♪
♪ 손바닥 위로 떨어진 은밀한 속삭임, 속삭임 ♪
The roots of our thoughts
생각의 뿌리는
wind and twist like a maze.
미로처럼 얽혀
Downward,
아래로
♪ Unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ 수수께끼를 풀고 ♪
we reach moist and fertile earth.
어둡고 축축한 흙 속을 파고들지
♪ It was you who gave me this brilliance ♪
♪ 내게 눈부신 빛을 선물한 건 너야, 바로 너 ♪
But for some reason,
하지만 알 수 없는
there is always a force that breaks through the darkness
거대한 힘이 마침내 어둠을 뚫고
♪ Lasting memories ♪
♪ 기나긴 기억 ♪
and grows upward toward the light.
위를 향해 자라난다
♪ The distance that brings our dreams closer ♪
♪ 꿈과 가까워진 거리 그 거리 ♪
♪ To run toward you ♪
♪ 너에게 달려가기 위해 ♪
♪ I keep practicing with no turning back ♪
♪ 난 거침없이 연습 또 연습해 ♪
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 널 향해 달려가 ♪
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 두려움 없이 앞으로 나아가 ♪
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪ 나란히 함께 ♪
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ 나 자신이 되어 ♪
♪ Amid the storm ♪
♪ 폭풍 속에서 ♪
♪ As our breaths slowly intertwine ♪
♪ 천천히 다가오는 숨결, 숨결 ♪
♪ Heartbeats alternating ♪
♪ 교차하는 심장 소리 ♪
♪ A chemistry about to emerge ♪
♪ 터져 나올 듯한 호흡, 호흡 ♪
♪ The stars are shining ♪
♪ 반짝이는 별빛 ♪
♪ Take my hand and run forward ♪
♪ 내 손을 잡고 앞으로 달려, 달려 ♪
♪ For you ♪
♪ 널 위해서라면 ♪
♪ I'm willing to keep practicing and practicing ♪
♪ 이렇게 몇 번이고 연습, 또 연습해 ♪
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪